<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dane Clark Collins</title>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:8080/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>http://localhost:8080</link>
    <description>Speculative Fiction Author &amp; Experimental Musician</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Of Dwarves and Artifacts: A SagaBorn Short Story</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/of-dwarves-and-artifacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/of-dwarves-and-artifacts/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Out with it,” barked the wizened old dwarf. Erl’s leather face shifted into a smile and he slapped Gartnor on the back with a stinging but friendly force. “The faster you ’splain what you want, the faster we can guzzle that pitcher.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I…uh…I’m not here to drink. I just…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Not here to drink, he says,” announced Erl to the raucous score of dwarves occupying the tavern. As hands wiped foam from ale-stained beards, their eyes turned suspiciously to Gartnor. “Not here to drink! Bwaah!” The group erupted in laughter. “Listen, lad, you don’t know our ways, so I’m going to tell ye. You come to us to ask a question. A question begs an answer. An answer is a favor. A favor is either returned, or it’s settled by the bond of drink. So you’ll ask, I’ll answer, and we’ll drink.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Fine, but then I really must go. You see…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Nay, lad…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You keep calling me lad,” interrupted Gartnor. “I have lived for fifty-four cycles.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And I for one-hundred and eighty-seven. So if ya don’t mind, I’ll call ye lad. Now listen, because I’m goin’ to teach ye some more about being polite to a score of dwarves. You never drink and run off, lad. No, you drink, and you hear our jokes, because they’re damn funny, aren’t they?” He addressed the question to the room, and was answered by a chorus of riotous cheers. “And then, once we’re spent, and the jokes are all told, we rest our weary hearts, minds, and bodies, with a little smoke of the pipe weed. We tell stories of dead heroes, and we might have us a cry. Only then, lad, do ye part ways from a company of dwarves. Understand?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gartnor’s eyes darted toward the door. “You know, I think I’ll just…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sentence trailed off as the room became quiet. “Nay, lad, you won’t. You see, you’ve already taken our time. You’ve gotten us curious. We’ll hear what you have to ask, and you’ll be polite. Ye’ll show us some courtesy, and when the sun is down and we’ve got tired in our bones, you’ll walk that pretty face back to the friends you have waitin’ in the inn. Now, ask.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I…uh…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Stop stuttering!” the tiny man roared. “Ye’ll make us uncomfortable. Ye’ll make us think ye don’t like us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m looking for something. I spent my life trying to track down an artifact. It was a family heirloom—before an ancestor lost it. I’ve tracked it to some agreement, four generations ago. A trade. It went to a company of dwarves around this area. I was hoping you could help me find it, and if someone still owns it, to negotiate the terms of its return.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So you want to reverse a trade? Let me tell ya another thing about dwarven manners…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It was our ancestors who made this deal. I’m not reversing. I’m asking for a new arrangement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And that’s how it works with you people, eh? If it wasn’t you, then a deal means nothing? Obligations don’t pass to kin, eh? Honor en’t taught? What was this artifact?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A jug. That’s all. It’s just a jug.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Is your ancestor called Duglan?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How do you…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It wasn’t my ancestor who made this deal, lad. Old Duglan traded with me. Your grandpops was toddling…couldn’ta been more’n two cycles. Your great grandpops was trying to get through the mountains with this toddler; somethin’ was huntin’ them. They were terrified, ya see. They came across us, and they begged us for help. We asked what they had for trade, and all they had was this jug.” He put his hand on the large, clay pitcher they had been drinking from. “So we took it for payment, and we saved your grandpop’s wee life, so that he could live to make the person that made you, so that you could come here today and show us this disrespect.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t mean…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You never mean!” After a long silence, the room burst into laughter. Again, the dwarf smacked Gartnor’s back, stinging the same spot as before. “The answer is no. We like this jug. My guess is you’re going to say there’s somethin’ magical about the old thing, and I wouldn’t be surprised. All the more reason to keep it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Now, I answered your question. The favor is done. You have nothing on you to return that favor, unless you want to walk out of here naked.” Gartnor shook his head. “Good. That’s the right answer.” A mug was shoved into his chest, spilling down his shirt, and he put his hands around it. “Drink!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gartnor took a drink, and was surprised to find it was the best malted ale he had tasted. Immediately, a good humor infused his body. “Ya see, now, lad, it’s not all so bad. No need for disappointment. Drink!” As he took another draught, Erl’s hand pushed up the cup, spilling liquid down Gartnor’s cheeks and forcing him to chug faster as he was cheered by the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Now sit down. Listen, lad, what do ya call an elf who marries a thundrom?”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Sci-Fi Horror Story: The Fifth Chalice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/horror-short-story-the-fifth-chalice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/horror-short-story-the-fifth-chalice/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This story has been bouncing around my mind for years, but two Octobers ago, inspired by the anticipation of Halloween, I finally put words down. Now, the story is published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;the-fifth-chalice-ebook-cover.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-right&quot; alt=&quot;The Fifth Chalice Front Cover&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A story of personal transformation gone terribly wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five friends stare at five golden chalices filled with mysterious elixirs. As they prepare to drink, they do not know what to expect, but they know that everything will be different—and in this world, different can only mean better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stan is the last to drink, and after watching his friends change, he refuses to drink from the fifth chalice. As his worst nightmares form before his eyes, he knows he must escape from his friends before he suffers their horrific fate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;purchase&quot;&gt;Purchase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fifth Chalice is available on Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/20PJzVy&quot; class=&quot;button center&quot;&gt;Buy from Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Horror Fantasy Short Story: Rosaga and the Man with Two Faces</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/new-horror-fantasy-short-story-rosaga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/new-horror-fantasy-short-story-rosaga/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;rosaga-ebook-cover.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-right&quot; alt=&quot;Rosaga and the Man with Two Faces Cover&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased to announce that I have a new short story up on both SagaBorn.com and Amazon. It is available in all major ebook formats for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sagaborn.com/store/rosaga&quot;&gt;free at SagaBorn.com&lt;/a&gt;, or if you’d like to read it on your Kindle, you can get it for &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1WN7bb2&quot; title=&quot;Purchase Rosaga and the Man with Two Faces at Amazon&quot;&gt;$0.99 on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;book-description&quot;&gt;Book description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A terrifying fantasy story from Dane Clark Collins, author of &lt;em&gt;Crossroads of the Never&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long after disappearing on a quest to chase his hallucinatory visions, Dreisin has resurfaced with a story stretching twelve hundred years into the past: a chilling tale of dark magic, cursed love, and a fate far worse than death. This is the tale of &lt;em&gt;Rosaga and the Man with Two Faces&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;button-group&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sagaborn.com/store/rosaga&quot; class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;Free at SagaBorn&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1WN7bb2&quot; class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;$0.99 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Problem of Evil in Fiction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/the-problem-of-evil-in-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/the-problem-of-evil-in-fiction/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I spoke on a panel with several other authors where we attempted to dissect the process of creating antagonists with depth. At one point, as I spoke about the word “evil,” a fellow writer in the audience became so severely offended that she grew visibly agitated, began mumbling expletives, then stormed out of the room in protest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did I say that was so offensive? I’ll try to paraphrase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An audience member had asked how we would define evil, and a part of my response was, “I try to avoid using the word evil. I believe that it oversimplifies something complex about human psychology, and doesn’t help us to solve the problems that we might call evil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The word ‘evil’ implies some fundamental, primordial, metaphysical force. It reinforces a binary worldview in which the world is neatly divided into forces of light and dark, good and evil. The truth is never that simple, and saying it is doesn’t get us anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I prefer to be more specific,” I continued. “I might speak of greed, or weakness, or cowardice. I would not,” I reassured the audience, “attempt to diminish the fact that people often do terrible things for terrible reasons. I simply don’t believe it helps us solve the problem by ascribing to them the motives of a cartoonish super-villain.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve paraphrased, but my actual words were quite close to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why, I ask, would this be such a controversial statement? It’s interesting to me that people often become angrier at the denial of an Ultimate Evil than the denial of the Ultimate Good. I understand that it’s comforting to live in an easily categorized world of simple binary judgments, but a writer—in my humble opinion—cannot have that luxury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m friends with many visual artists, and they often see the world in ways that are different from my own. They notice subtle color variations that I miss. They’re acutely aware of the composition of nature—the curves, the spirals, the waves. They notice anatomical details in other people. They pay close attention to the subtle visual cues that convey people’s moods and emotions. The average viewer of a painting may never understand the attention that a painter gave to those tiny details, but you can feel it subconsciously when you look upon a piece of great art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the same way, writers—as character builders—must notice the subtleties of human psychology and behavior. We must explore the inner worlds of our characters with empathy and understanding, even when we loathe our characters’ actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you assume that I dismiss the term out of ignorance, let me assure you that I have been the victim of what you would call “evil,” and I understand the temptation to toss it into the conceptual bucket of evil and never give it a second thought. But when I look at, for example, a serial killer, I see someone who is weak—unable to curb the most horrific of impulses. I see someone who will never know the beauty of empathy, love, and connectedness. This does not, in any way, diminish the damage and suffering the person has left in his or her wake. But attempting to define this behavior as it truly is, rather than attributing it to a force of simple evil, gives us a starting point from which we can try to explore and address the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is, I can sum up, no sin in my attempts to understand the adversary rather than to assign an easy category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the primary functions of a writer, in my opinion, is to remind people of the ambiguities, subtleties, and complexities of life that they may have forgotten; to remind people that behind every set of eyes, whether protagonist or antagonist, is a real person, with all the complexity of entangled feeling and motive that resides in the mind of a real person.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dead Gulch Funded, and to Include a Short Story by Dane</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/the-dead-gulch-funded/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/the-dead-gulch-funded/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the support from fans of SagaBorn, &lt;em&gt;The Dead Gulch&lt;/em&gt; has been funded, and has reached a special funding goal to include a short story written by me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;the-dead-gulch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Dead Gulch cover art&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-_the-dead-gulch_-&quot;&gt;What is &lt;em&gt;The Dead Gulch&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Dead Gulch&lt;/em&gt; is a Pathfinder Roleplaying Game-compatible role playing adventure designed for 4 to 6 characters of 2nd level. This adventure is part 2 of the &lt;em&gt;Ferryport Adventures: Return of the Fey&lt;/em&gt; adventure path, set in the Westlands of the dark continent of Atheles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The adventure is “node based”, which means that players can choose their own path, discovering locales and clues as they follow their investigations and intuitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The characters will advance from level 2 to level 4 by the end of the module. The book comes with 7 pre-made characters who all hail from different parts of Atheles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Dead Gulch&lt;/em&gt; is authored by Michael Bielaczyc, Shonn Everett, and Cameron Tomele, with some contributions and editing by me. It includes art by Melissa Gay, A.L. Ashbaugh, Michael Bielaczyc, Paul Bielaczyc, Christopher Burdett, Sam Flegal, Dennis Skotak, Robert Skotak, Alex Garrett, and Mitch Foust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-what-about-the-short-story-&quot;&gt;And what about the short story?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael included this as one of the funding goals (if funding went beyond what had been asked for): “A piece of short fiction by Dane Clark Collins will be included in the adventure.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll go ahead and let you in on what I’ve planned thus far: not a damn thing! I honestly had forgotten about this funding goal until a moment ago when I saw that it now says “unlocked.” But I have had some great ideas rolling around in my head, and most likely, you can expect this story to be a little unsettling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few people have said that Book 1 of &lt;em&gt;Crossroads of the Never&lt;/em&gt; left them wanting more, and they are frustrated they have to wait. Don’t worry, great progress has been made on the continuing saga of Toryn Ninefingers, and this short story won’t be a setback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;* Cover art by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.melissagay.com/&quot;&gt;Mellisa Gay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Trip to the Frank Frazetta Art Museum</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/frank-frazetta-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/frank-frazetta-museum/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is the first man whose art I feared. Actually, that’s not entirely true…there had been a few horror novels with covers that made me afraid, but that had been a surface fear. The dread conjured by a Frazetta painting was something deeper; it was visceral. His work was the first to transport me to a mythical world—an ancient and primitive world, where the terror of the unknown lurked in every shadow, dangerous even for the mightiest of men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember the cover of the first &lt;em&gt;Conan&lt;/em&gt; paperback by Lancer/Ace Books. This Conan was not a hero in gleaming armor, nor was he even a fearless warrior, confidently facing his enemies. Rather, Conan’s face here is a mix of terror and fury, facing his mortality against a primitive ape-like beast that is equally crying in terror and fury. This is not a battle of good versus evil. It is purely a battle of survival, and one or both of the combatants is about to suffer and die. The mood here is of brutal desperation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;frazetta_museum.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dane Clark Collins at the Frank Frazetta Museum&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read &lt;em&gt;Conan&lt;/em&gt;, and then I read the next book in that series, &lt;em&gt;Conan of Cimmeria&lt;/em&gt;. Again, I found myself mesmerized by the cover art as much as the words within. Again, we have Conan, not as a hero, but as a desperate man trying to survive. This time, he faces two massive men with axes and murderous intent. But it was not the antagonists, this time, that held my attention. It was the hopelessness and desolation of the environment. Conan faces his assailants alone in the secluded depths of frozen peaks. As with many of Frazetta’s paintings, the landscape is only vaguely detailed, and yet it is that hostile yet amorphous terrain that invokes such feelings of dread—the terror of becoming lost in those exposed peaks and tenebrous valleys that are only hinted at. Even if Conan comes out of this battle victorious, one might think, it appears likely he will soon be a frozen corpse, having died meaninglessly on some icy slope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my childhood, I can point to several turning points that led, bit by bit, to my desire to write. Those book covers (along with the stories within) are among the earliest and most profound. I wanted to invoke feelings that our mundane world can rarely reach—those fears that our modern society has left behind, but that our collective memory can still sense lurking in the recesses of our minds. I wanted to inspire the same primal awe and dread that Robert E. Howard and Frank Frazetta had inspired in me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve since experienced that same sense of awe and fascination in other works, such as Francisca Goya’s &lt;em&gt;Saturn Devouring His Son&lt;/em&gt;, or William Blake’s &lt;em&gt;Nebuchadnezzar&lt;/em&gt;. This puts Frazetta in good company. Sure, he did some highly commercial work and comic art that, despite its greatness, doesn’t quite stir the myth-fear-center of my mind the same way. But when the man tapped his well of inspiration, truly spiritual creations emerged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The museum is in Stroudsburg, PA, nestled in a remote riverside dale of the Pocono Mountains. This was Frank’s home that he designed himself, many years ago. It seemed the perfect home for such an artist, and the perfect location for his museum. I could imagine living and writing in such a place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The MidSouthCon 33 Report</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/midsouthcon-2015-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/midsouthcon-2015-report/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just returned from MidSouthCon 33, where I was invited to be an author guest. Here is my experience from the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;midsouthcon-33.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-right&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to start by thanking MidSouthCon for having me as a guest. This was my first MidSouthCon, and I felt I was treated quite well by the staff. The show was well-done, and aside from a couple of small hickups, everything went smoothly. I was able to meet fans of SagaBorn, meet other authors, form a couple of potential new partnerships, and get my book into the hands of some new readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pictured here is Paul Bielaczyc in his “Realistic Ice King” costume. He had just competed in the Masquerade. I had the privelege of watching Mike and Paul costume up before the competition and have gained a new respect for what cosplayers go through. Especially those with brothers mean enough to spray their nipples with cold, blue paint when they close their eyes. That happened. Both nipples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-panels&quot;&gt;My Panels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mythological-paranormal-and-regular-creatures&quot;&gt;Mythological, Paranormal, and Regular Creatures&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one started off with some difficulty. It began at 11 pm, and our moderator was replaced at the last minute. There was one other panelist, and we were all tired. But I believe we recovered and it became an interesting discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked of mythology, archetypes, technology and the creatures of the future, the continued evolution of humanity, the motivations and personalities of dogs and other creatures, and probably even more that I’ve forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;building-a-world-through-art-fiction-and-game-design-the-world-of-uteria&quot;&gt;Building a World Through Art, Fiction, and Game Design—The World of Uteria&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a great turnout for this one. Our crowd was engaged and asked many questions, so we thank them for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our panel included Michael Bielaczyc, Paul Bielaczyc, Melissa Gay (who was also the show’s Artist Guest of Honor), Sam Flegal, and me. We discussed many of the challenges we’ve faced in creating a multimedia world of gaming, art, and fiction, and the ways that we’ve attempted to overcome those challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;create-strong-characters&quot;&gt;Create Strong Characters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This panel, despite being at 9 pm on Saturday, packed the room and became a great conversation. This one included myself, Logan Masterson, Tracy Morris, Rosalie Stanton, Frank Tuttle, Jay Wilburn, and me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discussed the difficulties and procedures we use to create characters that have depth. We all agreed that the worst thing a writer can do is to create one dimensional characters that serve no purpose other than to move a plot along. So how does one add that depth? How does one add depth to a villain and avoid that villain being a simple force of pure evil? How does one find balance for a protagonist between flaws and relatability?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-closing&quot;&gt;In Closing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show had a few interesting issues arise. For instance, they put our booth in front of an exit, then came back to tell us we had to move. There were a few other odd moments as well, but they handled those situations well, and I believe we were all happy in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, I can only travel to one or two shows each year, so I have to take some care in my choice. I believe this is one I may go back to next year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don't Miss Dane's Appearance on Three Panels at MidSouthCon 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/panels-at-midsouthcon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/panels-at-midsouthcon/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MidSouthCon is Memphis is Dane’s first stop to promote his new book, &lt;em&gt;Crossroads of the Never: Book 1&lt;/em&gt;. Don’t miss him on his panels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MidSouthCon is March 20-22, 2015 in Memphis, TN. Most of the crew from Lone Wanderer Entertainment will be in attendance as author and artist guests, including myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be my first stop for promoting my new book, &lt;em&gt;Crossroads of the Never: Book 1&lt;/em&gt;, which has just become available in both paperback and Kindle eBook formats through Sagaborn.com and Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be doing three panels at MidSouthCon 2015, so if you’re in town for the show, you’ll want to attend them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;mythological-paranormal-and-regular-creatures&quot;&gt;Mythological, Paranormal and Regular Creatures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;March 20 at 11pm&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A discussion on the use of creatures, whether mythological, paranormal, or regular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;building-a-world-through-art-fiction-and-game-design-the-world-of-uteria&quot;&gt;Building a World Through Art, Fiction, and Game Design - The World of Uteria&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;March 21 at 10am&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This panel will discuss how the world developed though creative cooperation between the many facets of design. The world of Uteria is a fantasy world created by artist Michael Bielaczyc, but he has enlisted a whole team of talented people to help fulfill his vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;create-strong-characters&quot;&gt;Create Strong Characters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;March 21 at 9pm&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn to create three-dimensional characters readers will love and root for without going over the top. Does your dialog match your characters? Learn some ways to make characters more plausible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crossroads of the Never: Book 1—Now Available on Paperback and Kindle Ebook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/crossroads-of-the-never-amazon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/crossroads-of-the-never-amazon/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first book in &lt;em&gt;The Crossroads of the Never&lt;/em&gt; saga is now available in both paperback and Kindle eBook. Purchase through Sagaborn.com or Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;order-your-copy-now-&quot;&gt;Order your copy now…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to announce that &lt;em&gt;Crossroads of the Never: Book 1&lt;/em&gt;, my first book of fiction set in Atheles, is now available on both paperback and ebook through Sagaborn.com and Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sagaborn.com/store/crossroads&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to purchase the paperback through Sagaborn.com.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1508591652/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1508591652&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=danclacol-20&amp;linkId=Y5CYA7JBUSMSQOSK&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to purchase the paperback or Kindle ebook through Amazon.com.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More booksellers and ebook options will become available very soon, including B&amp;amp;N, iBooks, DriveThruFiction, and every other major online retailer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;book-description-&quot;&gt;Book description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;crossroads-cover.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Toryn Ninefingers, this is much like any other night, entertaining a rowdy crowd with song and story. But tonight, he has a special purpose in the telling of his tale, and reveals a shocking personal story that he has never told an audience before. With its telling, Atheles may never be the same again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first book in the &lt;em&gt;Crossroads of the Never&lt;/em&gt; saga, a series spanning thousands of years, shedding light on the dark and disturbing mysteries of the world of Uteria—a world besieged by the passing of a dark age, the continuing echoes of its violent history, and the recent incursion of creatures long since forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Cover Art for Crossroads of the Never: Book 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/cover-art-crossroads-of-the-never/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/cover-art-crossroads-of-the-never/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first book in the &lt;em&gt;Crossroads of the Never&lt;/em&gt; saga is coming soon. The cover art by Michael Bielaczyc has just been unveiled!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-so-it-begins-&quot;&gt;And so it begins…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;crossroads-cover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover Art for Crossroads of the Never&quot; class=&quot;img-right&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first book in the new series, the &lt;em&gt;Crossroads of the Never&lt;/em&gt;, has been completed. It is at the printer and the first proof is in the works. The book will become availabe in print as soon as it is ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to be emailed updates, please sign up for the mailing list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to thank Michael Bielaczyc for his help and support on this project, and especially for the incredible cover art that will grace the front of the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;book-description-&quot;&gt;Book description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Toryn Ninefingers, this is much like any other night, entertaining a rowdy crowd with song and story. But tonight, he has a special purpose in the telling of his tale, and reveals a shocking personal story that he has never told an audience before. With its telling, Atheles may never be the same again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first book in the &lt;em&gt;Crossroads of the Never&lt;/em&gt; saga, a series spanning thousands of years, shedding light on the dark and disturbing mysteries of the world of Uteria—a world besieged by the passing of a dark age, the continuing echoes of its violent history, and the recent incursion of creatures long since forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Having a Pronoid Worldview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/on-having-a-pronoid-worldview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/on-having-a-pronoid-worldview/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m of the opinion that human beings are bolstered by positive beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m also of the opinion that dogmatically held beliefs that attempt to cover all of reality are the greatest contributor to human suffering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do I reconcile these two positions? I attempt to find belief systems that are useful to my situation, but I keep those beliefs loose and flexible enough to change in response to my circumstances. It’s a difficult balance, but possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One belief system I find useful is the philosophy of pronoia (the opposite of paranoia). If you look around, and remain diligent in your search, you’ll see signs all around you that either a secret cabal or some other unseen force has conspired to help you, and perhaps to help all of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you hunt for conspiracies, you’ll always find them. This is partially because conspiracies abound in the world, and it’s also partially because the human mind is quite adept at turning loose connections into vast networks of clear cause and effect. If the conspiracies one finds are all sinister, then the world becomes a sinister place to live in. But if it’s a choice, then I’d rather not live in that world—the place where everyone is out to get me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a choice, of course. There are sinister forces in the world, and there are also benevolent ones. Most people are predominately benevolent, despite our tendencies toward greed and apathy. Given the choice, most of us would like to see everyone do better. If you need a reminder of the good in people, just find a photo of anyone holding a baby or a puppy. People have problems, and we often handle them poorly, but most of us want to be kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I look around, and I see vast network of cause and effect leading me toward a better place in a difficult world. Some force seems to be at work, guiding me unerringly where I need to go. It’s my choice whether to watch for the signs, but when I do, I’m rewarded. As a result, I’m a lucky person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On difficult days, when my luck seems to be failing, I watch for the signs. Inevitably, when the dust settles, I find myself in a better place than I was before. Perhaps I’ve learned a necessary lesson, and am better for it. Perhaps I’ve faced the destruction of some part of my life that, in retrospect, was holding me back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difficulty comes in those worst of times. There are occasions when it is damn near impossible, and perhaps even inappropriate, to think that what has occurred was for the best. Perhaps a friend or family member has died or is suffering from an illness or injury—that is not a time to rub your hands together and wonder what the conspiracy has in store for you. But that’s because life’s tragedies are not part of the conspiracy. Death and suffering are a part of the amoral, indifferent fabric of reality. They are inevitabilities, and no conspiracy could ever stop them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the conspiracy &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; help you get the support that you need. It can provide you with caring company so that you don’t have to suffer alone. Failing that, it can help you find peace in solitude. It can help you come away from the tragedy a better person than you were before. You only have to be diligent and watch for the signs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Guitar, and New Music Planned</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/a-new-guitar-new-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/a-new-guitar-new-music/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The unboxing of a new Damien 6 guitar by Schecter with a Sustainiac pickup has led to inspiration for new music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;schecter-guitar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dane's New Schecter Guitar with Bat Inlays&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with why this guitar is a great instrument, particularly for someone who likes to make a great variety of sounds…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sustainiac-pickup&quot;&gt;Sustainiac pickup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the neck position is a Sustainiac pickup. Those switches you see near the tremolo do two things: switch the sustain on and off and switch that sustain between three varieties: standard, harmonic, and mixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Sustainiac pickup allows a note to ring indefinitely. It uses magnetic feedback to make the string continue to vibrate. This allows for all sorts of sonic possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The possibilities are especially wide when you factor in the afforementioned harmonics mode, which will cause the strings’ harmonic tones to ring. Play a note, and it soon morphs into a squealing high-pitched tone. Slide the notes around, and all sorts of sounds emerge. Use the tremelo, and things get even weirder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bat-inlays&quot;&gt;Bat inlays&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This does nothing for the sound, but look at them! Bat inlays!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-music&quot;&gt;New music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t expect anything immediate, or even for the near future, but I am back in business as a musician.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an ambitious project well underway, and several songs nearly completed, I took a long hiaitus. My lack of motivation was probably due to losing all of the files for that project after losing both the hard drive and its backup. In addition, I began having a range of other technical difficulties, and it sapped my will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But music is compulsive for me, so it’s time to get back to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven’t settled on a particular project. I was considering playing around with instrumental guitar-heavy psychedelic strangeness. I’ve played guitar far longer than I’ve been recording, but I’ve never used my guitar very much in my recordings. I figure it’s time to change that. But we’ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a DAW, I’m trying out Reaper. So far, I think I may be enjoying it even more than Sonar, which was my DAW of choice in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jordancon 2014 Recap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/jordancon-2014-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/jordancon-2014-recap/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I attended Jordancon 6 (2014), the annual convention honoring the work of Robert Jordan (along, now, with other works of fantasy fiction). I had a panel to discuss the world of Uteria and we threw an incredibly fun launch party for the new book, &lt;em&gt;The Elves of Uteria&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;here-are-a-few-tl-dr-highlights-&quot;&gt;Here are a few tl;dr highlights:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Larry Elmore interpretive danced with Michael Bielaczyc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did I mention Larry Elmore was there? I was able to hang out with him a bit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Elves of Uteria&lt;/em&gt; launch party was a huge success. Many people came, and much alcohol was consumed. Books were signed, and a good time was had by all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michael Bielaczyc, Paul Bielaczyc, Sam Flegal, Melissa Gay, and I spoke on a panel called “Elves of Uteria: World Building.” It went much better than I had imagined it would, given my lack of public speaking skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creepy dolls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patrick Rothfuss was the Writer Guest of Honor. I watched several of his panels, and came away from each just a little bit smarter than I was before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brandon Sanderson was also in attendance, but my schedule never presented an opportunity to meet him or see one of his panels. Hopefully I’ll be able to make up for it in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;elves-of-uteria-jordancon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Elves of Uteria Launch Party at Jordancon 2014&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a great time, and as tired as I am, I’m a bit sad that it’s over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone for making it such an excellent event, especially the organizers and staff! They did a tremendous job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-launch-party&quot;&gt;The launch party&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/jordancon-2014-recap/party-jordancon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Elves of Uteria Launch Party&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part of the show, for us, was the &lt;em&gt;Elves of Uteria&lt;/em&gt; launch party. After a successful Kickstarter campaign and an expedited production cycle, we were ready to come to the show with a good number of printed hardbacks, which we sold quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the artists whose contributions appear in the book were in attendance, so we gave them all pens and ensured that anyone who got a book walked out with it looking much like a high school yearbook, filled with signatures and sketches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it’s time for Mike and I to begin preparations for the supplemental material that we promised in the Kickstarter, including an introductory module and city guide for Ferryport.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Come See Dane at Jordancon 6, 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/come-see-dane-at-jordancon-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/come-see-dane-at-jordancon-2014/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come visit me at the 6th annual Jordancon on April 11-13. The event will be held at the Doubletree Hotel in Roswell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be joining Michael Bielaczyc of Aradani Studios/Aradani Costumes for the launch of our new book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.daneclarkcollins.com/world-of-uteria/the-elves-of-uteria/&quot; title=&quot;The Elves of Uteria&quot;&gt;The Elves of Uteria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. We will be throwing a launch party that spans two suites and will offer free booze, because Mike knows how to throw a party!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book was cowritten by both Dane and Michael, and features Michael’s incredible paint work on the cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also at Jordancon will be several other artists from the book, including Sam Flegal, Paul Bielaczyc, Melissa Gay, and Larry Elmore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be hosting a workshop on April 12 entitled “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jordancon.org/sessions/elves-utera-world-building&quot; title=&quot;Elves of Uteria: World Building&quot;&gt;Elves of Uteria: World Building&lt;/a&gt;,” where we will tell of our journey in creating the world, and will be answering questions from the audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two New Songs from I Am the Phantom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/two-new-songs-i-am-the-phantom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2007 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/two-new-songs-i-am-the-phantom/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New I Am the Phantom tracks include Daily Progress and Gypsy Vagabond, two mellow songs guaranteed to turn your mind to gelatinous ooze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I Am The Phantom is an extremely experimental hip hop (of sorts) collaboration between myself, Squaw Music (Daniel Labrache), and Ryan Dennler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://daneclarkcollins.bandcamp.com/album/i-am-the-phantom&quot;&gt;Listen to the album here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video: Free Will (from Transient Revival)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/video-transient-revival-free-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2006 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/video-transient-revival-free-will/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is one of three videos from the Transient Revival piece, featuring animation by Michael Bielaczyc and music by Dane Clark Collins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;628&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6kzagR_WkkU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video: Aeon, Featuring Music by Dane Clark Collins</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/video-aeon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2006 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/video-aeon/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watch a brilliant animation created by Michael Bielaczyc, using the song &lt;em&gt;Curtains&lt;/em&gt; by Dane Clark Collins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;628&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/E0owcYbAsqY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transient Revival</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/transient-revival/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2006 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/transient-revival/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Renowned fantasy artist Mike Bielaczyc (Aradani Studios, Dragonlance) recently invited me to participate in the creation of an art exhibit of ambitious magnitude. My part was to create a soundscape that would enhance the atmosphere of an already dark and eerie exploration into the experience of belief, awakening, fate, and free will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The opening was tremendous, and we would like to thank everyone who made it out. I saw close friends, old acquaintances, people I haven’t seen in over a decade, and met quite a few new people…all coming together to witness Mike’s creation. My initial announcement regarding this project may have read like an extreme exaggeration, but as it turns out, it wasn’t an exaggeration in the least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you first walked out into the parking lot where it was setup, you were instantly greeted by real traveling vendors and entertainers. They came from all over the country to be a part of the show, all dressed in their traditional garb, selling costumes, art, pirate gear, and other rare and artistic valuables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the row of vendors and entertainers stood a giant tent shining solid white against the dingy foreground, rising high above the rest with its steepled top and symbol-shaped spire. Once making your way through the thick crowd of fairies, fire juggling, pirates, and tuxedo-garbed satyrs, you then found yourself at the entrance to the tent. Before walking in, you could already hear the torturous sounds that would set the tone for the eerie experience that awaited inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside the tent was the core of this project—the product of months of difficult, diligent, costly, and sometimes even bloody labor. From the ceiling hung a ceramic phallic spiraled beehive dripping honey from its tip into a white ceramic baptismal bowl. To the right was a screen embedded into the tent wall, playing a nightmarish video of bees, jellyfish, and a clay man slowly drowning in the baptismal honey. To the left was a screen playing a video that also included bees, jellyfish, and baptism, only in this one Mike’s own face wore the honey, which slowly ascended upward off of his face allowing him to finally open his eyes and experience a new awareness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The revolving crowd of onlookers on the inside was consistently pressed thick, with word of mouth spreading and everyone packing in to watch the full animations. In the time I spent inside, I heard only authentic praise and appreciation for the work that was obviously put into its creation, and for the atmosphere and originality of the final result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the project will be on display at Watkins for the next month, and soon Mike will be putting the animations together with the music so that it can be viewed online. The music will be posted separately on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inhumangenome.com/&quot;&gt;InhumanGenome.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dane Heads to Nashville for an Art Showing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/dane-heads-to-nashville-for-art-showing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2006 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/dane-heads-to-nashville-for-art-showing/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Michael Bielaczyc has created an ambitious work of art which will be on display on the 10th, and it is accompanied by sounds so beautifully ugly that I have to be there to hear them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know exactly what dates yet, and will post them when I know exactly, but I’ll be in Nashville the weekend of November 10th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mike’s project is going to be a sight to behold, and I insist that everyone I know, even if you live in Sweden (you know who you are) make it out to help bear witness to this monumental display. If you know anyone in the media, they’ll want to see this, so tell them to bring their cameras. Do NOT let them miss this tremendous opportunity for a Pulitzer Prize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the show we’ll be drinking obscene amounts of alcohol in the nude and will gather atop the tower at Tiger Hill to partake in a world record breaking orgy. Guinness will be there to record the entire event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is, it’s going to be a weekend to remember, and if you don’t make it, you’re going to die wishing you hadn’t lived such a dull and lonely life. Be there, that’s all I’m saying.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>